Caroline Bates

Perth, Western Australia

Phone: 0466521978 | Email: caroline.portilla@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://github.com/CazB67 | Portfolio: https://cazb67.github.io/responsive-portfolio/

Summary

I am a Front End Web Developer leveraging a background in special education and primary teaching to build accessible and responsive web applications. I earned a certificate in Full Stack Development from the University of Western Australia Coding Bootcamp in 2020, and developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, JQuery, Node JS, MySql, MongoDB, REACT and responsive web design. For the last 3.5years I have worked developing an application that allows jobseekers to create video job applications and allows recruiters and businesses to manage those applications. I am known as organised and hardworking with a flair for the creative. I am very driven to ensure a positive and smooth user experience and am excited to use my skills to develop applications that solve existing problems and exceed clients' expectations.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Javascript, JQuery, Github, Media Queries, JSON, Technical writing, React, Responsive design, Typescript, Task management

Find Surf Spot App

Projects

- An application that uses Willy Weather API to recommend the best surf sports in the Perth metropolitan area.
- Cooperatively and efficiently working in a group of three using Agile software development (Kanban) Github and the command line.
- Role included website design using Foundation Framework, familiarisation with Google Maps Embed API and how it works to display maps on the page.
- Deployed link: https://cazb67.github.io/find-surf-spot-app/
- Github: https://github.com/CazB67/find-surf-spot-app

Basketball Stats

- An application where users can record the statistics of a basketball player in real time so that they can assess their progress over time.
- Featuring nodejs, CSS, express, mongoose and Passport authentication
- Individually planned and developed using Github and the command line a working and useful app within the designated time frame.
- Deployed link: https://node.bates.codes
- Github: https://github.com/CazB67/basketball-stats

Experience

UseVerb Pty Ltd

September 2020 - April 2024

Software Developer

- Front end software developer using React JS and Typescript to develop a responsive web application that used a messaging system and video application for jobseekers to apply to jobs and business to view and sort video applications.
- Proficient in React Js and Typescript Developed various features and components that communicated with the API to display and update data to the user.

- Quality Assurance Extensive experience in ensuring product quality through rigorous testing and evaluation processes.
- Bug Fixing and Bug Identification Skilled in identifying, diagnosing, and resolving software bugs to enhance overall system performance. Used Trello and ClickUp to track these.
- Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) Proficient in optimising website content to improve search engine rankings and visibility.
- Breaking down larger tasks into smaller manageable subtasks
- CSS Styling Proficient in creating visually appealing and mobile responsive user-friendly interfaces with Cascading Style Sheets.
- Production Releases Adept at managing and executing production releases, ensuring smooth deployment of software updates and communicating updates to the rest of the team
- Code Reviews Experienced in conducting thorough code reviews to maintain high coding standards and improve code quality.
- Change Management Skilled in managing and adapting to changes in software development processes and technologies.
- Team Collaboration Planning, problem solving and knowledge sharing between team members

Department of Education WA

January 2015 - December 2019

Relief Teacher

 Primary and education support teacher at various schools covering different ages, abilities and for varying lengths of times showing adaptability and resourcefulness. Class Professionals January 2012 - December 2019

Tutor

 Helping primary aged students to achieve improved outcomes in literacy and numeracy by developing strategies for learning.

Merriwa Education Support Centre

Feb - June 2011

Classroom and relief teacher

• Provided middle and upper primary support showing adaptability and excellent collaborative skills.

Roseworth Education Support Centre

2010

Classroom teacher

• Teaching a senior primary class of children with special needs and challenging behaviours life skills and working with them to transition campuses and prepare for high school.

Education

University of Western Australia (2020): Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Edith Cowan University (2010): Graduate Certificate of Education (Special Education)

Murdoch University (2002): Graduate Diploma in Education (Primary)

Murdoch University (2001): Bachelor of Marketing and the Media